Number 20
and it
took me a long time to find a
photograph of someone pouring
water into a good cup of coffee and
ruining it. I do
n't know if you've ever done that. They have
enough to
do for three people, and then
the fourth person arrives, and then I... I already had
this... with four children and
no husband,
so they paid me on Fridays. Then on
Saturdays we drank orange juice. On
Thursdays, it came to Sunday. On Sundays
we drank half water, half
diluted orange juice. Monday was
Monday, and it was more diluted, and by
Friday it was just a
little weird color.
And there's a tradition of the refuge, which is what you do
n't dilute. Your refuge, don't mix
other things in there.
You hear things from people
[Music]
like I like the idea that you
can fix the air conditioner
by helping someone else fix their
air conditioner. That's what people say,
but after that, yes, but that's an
idea, but let's not be practical. I understand that's
the point of view of the weapon,
but the practical point of view... you
have to see it, say, we
get to the point that the point of view
of seeing things from the sea  It has to
be practical too, so they tell you, I don't
know, it's practical, don't go to the
wire, and all the time, yes, but that's what I
'm doing, I have to do
everything because I have nothing, I want to have a
successful relationship, I want to be healthy,
this is the most practical thing,
this is what works, so don't dilute
your efforts in
the shelter, even if 50% is nothing, or
Gisela, I trust that I helped
other people, I'm going to have a good
business, but you know, I think I have to
cheat a little to get there, you do
n't know how many people tell me that, they don't say it like that,
but they mean that,
and when we get to this section in the
book later on, it's a tough section
because it's very critical
of the things that don't work,
and he picks up some other
worldviews that during his life, in
his time and in his country, like there was a
viewpoint
called Bond
[Music],
people paid them weekly,
and they believed that the world was created
by this person,
and they had a belief, well, they still
exist,
and some people told this
lama, "
My parents were like that," in my parents  And
they thought the world was
created by sowing seeds or something,
and I kind of prefer it to be 50-50. And I
wonder, is that okay?
Well,
I'm going to fix
someone else's air conditioner, but I'm also going to believe
in nonsense. And saying that you keep
doing that is like with orange juice, it's
not going to be very strong, the shelter isn't going to
be very strong. So it depends on
you. I don't want to be disrespectful to
your parents, I don't want that. I go to Mass. I
went to Mass two
weeks ago,
and it makes my family happy, and I
learn good things,
and that's fine. But maintain
your correct worldview,
don't dilute it, don't water it down, don't add water to a
good Starbucks coffee.
Everything comes from everything, 100%. It's not made
50/50. It comes from 100/50, it comes from
something or something else. Don't maintain
that point of view. I have some friends who
are very close Christians, and they
ask me, "Can I believe in God too?" I tell
them, "If you don't have any problem, it
comes from you,
that's fine, just like a person
can come from me."  It comes to taking care of you, this is
your mother, you exist, your father is
possible and it's okay. In Buddhism
we say Bayern yoga and it didn't make the world,
but I did, go to Bayern hyung jin, and
that's fine.
But underneath that is this belief that
everything comes from you
and as a result of how you have
treated people. And I don't think they
contradict
the main religions. And if you study
the 30 pages of the New Testament, the
words of Jesus Christ
[Music],
we should get this
whole conversation about planting
seeds in the ground,
sowing stones in different soils. And
Jesus talks about these things, and
Muhammad is the same,
so there's no problem.
But don't put water in your [unclear]
because it's not going to help us.
Everything comes from you, everything is fine, everything is the
result of how you treat people. And
all this point,
I think it depends on that meditation. You
can think, "
I'm diluting my understanding."
We are the seeds.
How much can you believe that the cell phone comes
from you? 20, 30%? Try to raise your
percentage.
Try to always raise your
And if it always comes from me, and it's another part.
The prayer of how I treat
people always comes from me, from how I have
treated other people,
and the partitions, the construction
of existence, are
not atoms, they are kindnesses. You have to
get to that, you have to get
to feel that in your heart.
This computer is not made of atoms
and silicon and copper atoms.
Those copper atoms are made of kindness.
If it has atoms of steel and copper and
silicon, but its atoms are held
together thanks to the kindness in how I
have treated people, and you have to
get to think, it's the place sooner or
later
in your life.
Let's see how we get to that.
If the question is, there is a number 3 button,
which means that it says after you
take refuge in the Sangha, then we are
suggested that we do not associate too
closely with people who think that
all this is crazy. That means you ca
n't have
Christian or Muslim friends. It doesn't mean that.
What is the sign of good refuge?
It is to be good to all people. It can't be that you do
n't believe that
copper atoms were made because of kindness,
then I don't like you.
[Music]
and  I pray and cry because that
organization should never become that, and
I don't know how. We have to be very
careful.
I taught the 18 steps in
teacher training, how to
teach the pen
second by second, how to teach the
pen, and we spent 12 hours on 18
different things you have to do in
the 2-minute pen presentation.
Then a week later, he tells me, "Hey,"
and they said, "I don't think it's 17." And in my
mind, this is an idea of
the future:
the 17-step religion into the
18-step religion, and they're going to
hate themselves and have wars.
So we have to be very careful
that something like that doesn't happen to us.
So this
vow is dangerous. What it means is,
this is very difficult. You have to try to
protect
your worldview from the whole world. The
whole world believes in copper atoms.
Everyone, every religion, every person
in the world has the same
religion, which is called science. Copper atoms
are the very act of copper.
And so try to pass it on when you choose
your friends.  Close friends, choosing
friends who, for example, Cristian's mom,
was when I was talking
about 10 ways to raise money in a
very strange way, and it
made me feel very uncomfortable. Choose, you're
fine, and I know what you're thinking, and she
told me it's not about helping other
people
raise money, it's about helping them raise
money for their organizations, and you
want those kinds of people around,
that's all.
You want to be close to people who
can correct you, Maicon, when you
have other ideas, so that's what she
means.